Kathleen Barbour

1221 Hall Rd., West Chester PA 19380 (C) 610.883.1250 (E) kbarbour1970@gmail.com

Professional Summary

It is my goal to combine my range of experience with my ability to be a compassionate, enthusiastic, intelligent, and an energetic educator who will make a positive contribution to your school. I have a talent for involving and motivating students of all ability levels. The ability to relate effectively to students of diverse cultural backgrounds and to tailor teaching methods to suit their individual needs. Excellent written and verbal communication skills, with the ability to convey concepts in an accessible and compelling manner. Strong leadership qualities and the ability to manage challenging behavior calmly and effectively. The ability to establish positive relationships with fellow professionals and parents. A genuine interest in and respect for young people. Responsibilities in education: Providing a stimulating learning environment in which students can develop to their full potential. Employing a broad range of instructional techniques to retain student interest and maximize individual learning within a group environment. Helping to prepare students for the future workforce by introducing new technology and encouraging interactive group-work and problem-solving.. Preparing and implementing remedial programs for students requiring extra help. Providing assistance with career guidance, job placement and follow-up work with students.

Core Qualifications

- Quick learner
- Proficiency in modern technology
- Excel in Biology
- SMART Board familiarity
- Microsoft Office and Outlook proficiency
- Calm under pressure
- Experience working special needs students
- Active participation in NSTA

- Pennsylvania Teaching License
- Kind and empathetic
- Urban public schools background
- Creative lesson planning
- Critical thinker
- · Positive and encouraging
- Adept classroom manager
- Active listening skills

Experience

08/2014 to present

Devon Preparatory School

Devon, PA

- Teach Students Anatomy & Physiology, and Molecular Biology
- Mentor Students
- Before and after school tutoring
- Apply differentiated instruction in my lessons
- Assist with student rallies, assemblies, and extra-curricular activities
- Coach the Bowling Team and Science Olympiad
- Complete continuing education courses online

09/2013-6/2014

Moyer Academic Institute

Wilmington, DE

- Teach students grades 7-12 Math and Science integrating technology
- Student Adviser
- Maintain accurate computerized grades
- Developed interesting course plans to meet academic, intellectual and social needs of students.
- Earned positive verbal/written feedback from parents regarding classroom instruction and student learning success.
- Routinely met with students' parents regarding in-class issues and learning interruptions to discuss solutions.

10/2010 - 06/2012	La Academia	Lancaster, PA			
	 Teach students grade 7-12 Integrated Science, Earth and Space Science. Working with inner city students to motivate them to achieve more. Developed interesting course plans to meet academic, intellectual and social needs of students. Earned positive verbal/written feedback from parents regarding classroom instruction and student learning success. Routinely met with students' parents regarding in-class issues and learning interruptions to discuss solutions. 				
08/2008 - 05/2010	 interruptions to discuss solution Used variety of teaching discussion in 9th grade Geton Developed, administered at Received high remarks for instructional techniques from Earned positive verbal/writinstruction and student learned 	ts' parents regarding in-class issues and learning utions. techniques to encourage student critical thinking and neral Science course. nd corrected tests and quizzes in a timely manner. r the creativity of classroom lesson plans and m students, parents and faculty. tten feedback from parents regarding classroom			
01/2008 - 06/2008	Garnet Valley High School Glen Mills, PA Para-Professional				
	Follow students through claTake notes and obtain worl	n teachers with the students. asses to give them one on one assistance. ksheets for absent students. croom with classwork and understanding.			
08/2001 - 06/2007	St Norbert Elementary School Paoli, PA Science Coordinator/ Middle School Teacher				
E location	 increase concentration, par Earned positive verbal/writerinstruction and student lear Designed lesson plans focution Developed, administered a 	with effective measures and various lesson plans to rticipation, and progress student accountability. Iten feedback from parents regarding classroom rning success. Sused on age and level-appropriate material. Indicorrected tests and quizzes in a timely manner. It is parents to update them on student progress.			
Education	Immoulate University	Immagulata DA LISA			
2001	Immaculata University, Immaculata, PA, USA Bachelor of Arts in Biology with a minor in Secondary Education.				
Professional Affiliations	Immaculata University, Immaculata, PA Continuing my Masters in Educational Leadership. Expected graduation date: 5/2017				
	National Science Teachers Association NSTA Pennsylvania Science Teachers Association PSTA				
Accomplishments	County IU and NASA	nership in Math and Science) between the Chester MS: a grant partnership between Lancaster IU and			